<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-30T13:17:39-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/</id><title type="html">Doug Skinner’s Blog</title><subtitle>My own thoughts and opinions on software engineering topics, wider technology, people, and what ever else comes up.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Flask Template</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/23/flask-template.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flask Template" /><published>2018-01-23T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/23/flask-template</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/23/flask-template.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is still a work in progress&lt;/strong&gt;. This project aims to be a template for other web developers to base their
projects off of. The template includes a couple of classes that handle creating
users, logging in users, and eventually managing users. Each user upon logging
in is presented with their own control panel for whatever service they are
logging into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As stated above, this project is a work in progress, and I will be posting updates below as they happen, and updating through blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is still a work in progress. This project aims to be a template for other web developers to base their projects off of. The template includes a couple of classes that handle creating users, logging in users, and eventually managing users. Each user upon logging in is presented with their own control panel for whatever service they are logging into.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Downloading Isn’t Stealing</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/22/More-NN-Thoughts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Downloading Isn't Stealing" /><published>2018-01-22T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/22/More-NN-Thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/22/More-NN-Thoughts.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Warning&lt;/strong&gt;: This post is very long. Read at your own risk.&lt;br /&gt;
Also as part of my class discussed previously, I had to write a term paper on
any topic that my little heart desired, as long as it related to the class. The
topic was copyright law in the online realm, and what follows is the paper. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently there is a conversation ongoing within the United States about stealing. This discussion however, isn’t about the theft of physical property. The discussion is instead focused on the common act among internet users of copying and sharing files and whether that should be considered stealing according to United States law. Currently according to the United States Code, Title 17: Sections 501 and 506 (17 U.S. Code § 506), any unauthorized copying is against federal law, and the law prescribes severe civil and criminal penalties for the act. This law, and the punishments defined within are based on treating the digital copying of files, called digital theft, the same as physical theft. Based on the actions of most individuals within society however, the argument can and should be made to not treat the actions as equivalent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Reynolds, intellectual property is the “term used to describe works of the mind—such as art, books, films, formulas, inventions, music, and processes—that are distinct and owned or created by a single person or group.” (Reynolds, G. 2014). This intellectual property is governed through various governments through copyright, patent, and trade secret laws. The two sets of laws that most frequently govern the acts of copying online files are copyright laws and patent laws, protecting art, books, film, and music or inventions respectively. According to Article 1, Section 8, Clause 8 congress shall have the power “to promote the Progress of Science and useful Arts, by securing for limited Times to Authors and Inventors the exclusive Rights to their respective Writings and Discoveries.” (Article 1, Section 8, Clause 8. 2000). Also, according to Reynolds, a copyright is the “exclusive right to distribute, display, perform, or reproduce an original work in copies or to prepare derivative works based on the work.” (Reynolds, G. 2014). Any person found to be in violation of the rights held by a copyright holder is committing copyright infringement. According to current United States law the courts have much ability to pursue or make example cases of copyright infringement, as they have the power to award fines anywhere from $200 to $100,000. Current copyright law guarantees the holder to the rights to their work for a period of several years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bidding of lobbyists from those who stand to gain a lot by extending copyright, the term of copyright has been extended 11 times in the timespan starting in 1960. The people primarily behind the lobbyists are mostly movie studios and other large holders of multiple copyrights to merchandising empires. The reason behind fighting so hard for copyright extensions is that the studios make most of their profit from selling toys, movies, and other tie-ins for their various iconic properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original term of copyright was twenty-eight years, however the Copyright Term Extension Act signed into law in 1998 sets out the time limits outlined as follows (COPYRIGHT TERM EXTENSION):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For works created after January 1, 1978, copyright protections endure for the life of the author plus 70 years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For works created but not published or registered before January 1, 1978, the term endures the life of the author plus 70 years, but also guarantees that it expires no earlier than December 31, 2004.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For works created before 1978 that are still within their original term of copyright the total term is to be extended to 95 years from the original date of copyright.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this act was signed into law, it was challenged by Eric Eldred. Eldred wanted to create an online library of sorts, where older books would be available for viewing to those who otherwise wouldn’t have access to them. The Eldred v. Ashcroft case went all the way to the United States Supreme Court, which upheld the act as constitutional in 2003. After the Supreme Court made this decision, many internet activists revolted against it, not unlike what occurred during the attempted passing of PIPA and SOPA in 2012. The activists attempted to get Congress to change the law through appeals directly to its members, and even started a campaign to amend the Constitution (Wu, T. 2003). Other members of the internet activist groups however fought to fix this wrong doing another way. The activists argued that as they had the power to write code to either enforce the law or allow it to be broken easier, that power should be used to directly influence the publics conformance or not with the law. While that is not to say that the activists directly encouraged the breaking of the law, it can be stated that the like great tax lawyers can find loopholes within the tax code, great programmers and activists should likewise look to exploit the copyright protections within any possible legal loopholes (Wu, T. 2003). Thus, semi-organized resistance to copyright law was discussed for the first time regarding the digital realm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major defenses used by these activists, and unfortunately those who do go on to break the law, is the concept of the Fair Use Doctrine. Renyold’s defines it as “allowing portions of copyrighted materials to be used without permission under certain circumstances.” (Reynolds, G. 2014). The United States Code, according to Title 17 Section 107 states that “the fair use of a copyrighted work, including such use by reproduction in copies or phonorecords or by any other means specified by that section, for purposes such as criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching (including multiple copies for classroom use), scholarship, or research, is not an infringement of copyright.” (17 U.S. Code § 107). The law also outlines the following four considerations to use when determining whether a specific use of a copyrighted work falls within fair use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The purpose and character of the use, including whether such use is of a commercial nature or is for nonprofit educational purposes;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The nature of the copyrighted work;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The amount and substantiality of the portion used in relation to the copyrighted work as a whole;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finally, the effect of the use upon the potential market for or value of the copyrighted work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The law also concludes by stating that the above guidelines are to be used whether the copyrighted work is published or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An application of the Fair Use Doctrine in 2011 was when the HathiTrust Digital Library had a lawsuit filed against them by the Authors Guild, an advocacy group for writers. The reasoning behind the lawsuit was that multiple digital copies of a work or text were created through the simple act of building the library, that HathiTrust Digital Library was violating copyright by reproducing copyrighted works without the explicit permission of each copyright holder. While the courts did eventually side with the library, stating that by transferring the works from a written form to digital form the library was falling under transformative use, an all too common counter point to this ruling is the continued prosecution of those who share music or other forms of media digitally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the book “What if We Could Re-Imagine Copyright”, Christophe Geiger argued that copyright protections are key to the continued survival of many forms of creative expression (Geiger, C. 2017). While Geiger does acknowledge that copyrights are mostly beneficial for large corporations, he still argues for the continued use of copyright. The argument can be made that artists will be loath to continue producing content without the knowledge that their work will be free from copying, however in modern times it seems that this is no longer the case. This can be seen in the large number of people creating songs, videos, and other creations and either open-sourcing the contents or uploading them to platforms where the platform owner holds the ownership of the content. This counter-argument can then be extended to considering if people are willing to give up ownership of a work entirely, that there should be no qualms about the sharing of their content to new audiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once someone follows this train of thought, it begs the question of whether copying digital bits to a friend is ethical instead of illegal. Once taken out of the realm of legality into the realm of everyday thought, it seems remarkable that this conversation has even continued in the days of easy access to everything online. While the law unfairly equivocates downloading a copyrighted work with common law stealing, what should be considered the more important question to an individual that is about to commit this act is how a group of their peers, also known as a jury, would see this action. The reason this is important is that while the laws of a country are seemingly set in stone, in most developed countries it is the will of the people, again that group of your peers, that can help shape and change the way the law works. This process of change allows the laws to be continually updated to reflect what society considers to be unethical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the topic can be discussed, a brief description on the difference between illegal (legal) and unethical (ethical) is necessary. Legal means something recognized or made effective by a court of law as distinguished from a court of equity, whereas ethics is defined as the moral principles of an individual. Defined in plain English, for an action to be illegal it must be against a written law, whereas an action must be considered immoral to a person to be ethically wrong. Now, a definition of moral, sanctioned by one’s conscience, will be helpful here. While legality is based on written laws which are notoriously hard to change in the United States no matter how easy that should be, ethicality is based on one’s own belief of what is right and wrong. And, as can be seen on Wiring the Brain (Mitchell, K. 2011, June 13), the morals of one person come from those around the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this fact has been accepted, it is not that far of a jump to conclude how a law is originally created. A law is a cemented moral based upon a specific point in time. As anyone who’s ever watched the American political system flounder to change the laws put into place by the previous administration has learned, laws are difficult to change simply because they are easily defended by those who they protect. What does this mean? Well, it means that while morals evolve based on what a group of people currently think, laws are based upon what a group decided to write down at some point in the past. This means that there is going to naturally be some drift between the two of these points. And due to the difficulty of changing the written laws, the gap only increases over time. So, while everyone can agree, at least within the United States, that downloading content that you don’t currently have an agreement to have access to is illegal the real question is to whether this same act is unethical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This depends entirely upon what society currently thinks, and I think that the argument can be made that society agrees that downloading is not stealing which goes back to the definition of stealing. The definition of stealing is defined as follows: party A has an item, and party B doesn’t; Party B then takes the item from party A; Now party B has it and party A doesn’t. This is a zero-sum problem, where only one party can have the item at once. That’s why common theft is considered both illegal and unethical as it means that one person’s loss is another person’s gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloading an item, such as an mp3 file, is not zero sum however. If an mp3 is taken, copied it, and given to another party the first party still has their copy of the mp3 and now someone else does too. This means that both parties have the file, resulting in one person’s gain and another person’s neutral. It should be easy to agree that between having a zero-sum vs a positive sum outcome, the positive sum is more desired. And if the outcome is more desired, there is absolutely no reason that it should be made, or continue to be, against the law. And it seems that most of current American society would agree with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/Piracy_Percentages_Wide.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Mick, J. 2013, January 21)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another argument for the easing of copyright laws is that most great works of history have been derivative in some manner. A derivative work is an expressive creation that includes major elements of an original copyright protected work, without consisting entirely of the original work. According to law, the work must be considered original and bear the marks of the new artist in order to be truly derivative instead of simply copying. While one of the most famous examples of a derivative work, the LHOOQ, is simply a joke consisting of the Mona Lisa painting originally created by Leonardo da Vinci repainted to include a moustache, there is no reason to believe that is the only form of derivative work. Most media that the American public consumes is derivative in some way. Late night comedy shows almost entirely consist of poking fun at the actions of those around them within society, or mocking popular culture elements of TV Shows. Considering TV shows, two of the most popular shows in America Family Guy and The Simpsons are incredibly derivative, as both shows not only have entire characters that are simply parodies of characters, both real and cartoon, but also have entire episodes that consist of making fun of another show or movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples such as these aren’t limited to TV shows, as movies and books have done the same thing. After the Lord of the Rings became a popular book, the entire genre of fantasy consisting of made up worlds with original languages and creatures that never existed before exploded into popularity. Harry Potter serves as another book that helped to spark the love of fantasy within another generation of society. Similarly, the book Dune is considered a large part of the popularity of Science Fiction, and the entire Star Wars franchise is entirely based off the success of the first movie, A New Hope, that is considered by many critics to be almost an entire rip off of the story from Dune (Kunzru, H. 2015, July 03). Disney, the new owners of Star Wars, are not unfamiliar with the concept of derivative works themselves, as most of their popular movies are based on simply taking stories from the Fairy Tales Grimm, making them appropriate for children by taking out references to death, murder, and the gruesome bits, and marketing them as if they were originally created by Disney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to original example of the LHOOQ, most painters are very derivative as they grow upon the designs and ideas of those that came before them. Or, sometimes this takes the shape of going the other direction. An artist may consume so much of one type of media only to ensure that they go the entirely opposite direction to be original. However, originality only for the sake of not being derivative can be even be considered derivation itself as you must consume enough of a topic to make sure that your implementation doesn’t include anything that’s in the original. Finally, probably the most derivative genre of media of all is music, for many of the same reasons as painting. Music goes even further as many of the most popular songs nowadays are nothing more than rehashes of those that came before. An example recently in the news was when one rap artist produced a song, a second rap artist then remixed that song into another using the first as a hook. The original artist then took the song created by the second and used it as a hook for a third song. Creating a song of a song of a song is something that is only possible according to current societal morals as both artists didn’t care that the other took their work as it is commonplace among the music community. There is no reason that the same can’t be said for other communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information is power (Swartz , A. 2008, July). Many in history have said that before, and many will say it in the years to come. However, like all power in society there are those that want to make it so that they remain in power by keeping information, knowledge about everything within society to themselves. A perfect example of this is anyone who wants to read previous scientific and cultural research on a topic. This information is being increasingly held by a handful of private companies, that want to charge enormously large amounts of money to access that information. It is a sad fact that currently the final step in the research of many doctoral students is to turn in their paper, get it peer reviewed, accepted into the community, and then hand over the keys to the kingdom to those already in power. The knowledge gained is then held by the doctoral student, anyone who read it previously, and now anyone that want to pay online databases roughly a $100 per article for access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The online database companies take these matters very seriously, even pursuing legal actions against those who try to work around the safeguards that they have in place to stop the spread of knowledge. The most famous of these court cases involving JSTOR, notably the most well-known of the article stores, and a young man named Aaron Swartz. While on the campus of the Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Swartz had started downloading articles from JSTOR. While anyone on the campus has full access to JSTOR using their web portal, Aaron had written a script to simulate browsing the website to download multiple articles at once as fast as the computer could. All told, he got multiple hard drives worth of data for an unknown purpose. Swartz had said that he was using the papers he gathered for research purposes, something that is entirely within the rights of a JSTOR user. JSTOR, however, declared that he must be downloading the articles for the nefarious purpose of trying to open his own competing article database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the copyright laws that were stated within the first couple pages of this article and the Computer Fraud and Abuse Act of 1986, JSTOR brought legal action against Swartz, which involved him getting arrested by an FBI team. This eventually lead Swartz to be charged with multiple felonies and the chance of being ordered to pay restitution of over a million dollars. A million dollars, for what? Downloading some articles that anyone in the world that can make it to Boston can access for free? The prosecution ended abruptly when Aaron was found dead after the case was once again continued. While this may seem like an extreme example, this could become increasingly commonplace if the copyright laws aren’t adjusted to be realistic with the society of today that involves the use of so much online data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without completely rehashing the arguments made above, it can be said that the main arguments for the changing of copyright laws are the differences between what is written law and what is believed by the common man, the effect that sharing works on knowledge can have, and how copyright serves to gate-keep that knowledge from those that need it the most. Through the surveys outlined above, it has been proven multiple times that the average person in America either sees no problem with internet piracy or is a pirate themselves. Since most seem okay to commit the act, it is highly doubtful that they believe that they should be prosecuted for breaking a law that is so out of touch with their actions and the actions of those around them. It is also clear to see that many works nowadays and in the past, are derivative in nature, whether that is painters and composers taking inspiration from their peers to the newer fascination that rappers and hip-hop artists have with remixing each other’s songs either adding a new rap verse or taking the chorus of one song to use as the refrain to another. Without the ability to do this, many of these artists would not be able to make the kinds of or amount of music that they currently do. Finally, in this day and age especially considering the number of times that this has gone wrong in the past it is frankly ridiculous that there should be keepers of knowledge. While there should always be libraries to store knowledge, the cost of obtaining that knowledge should be either physically getting to the library or navigating to the libraries webpage, not paying sometimes hundreds of dollars per article to access that information. Every time in history this same setup has occurred of those privileged few with access to all the knowledge leaving the plebeians with starvation of the mind, there has been some catastrophic event that causes the loss of all that knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Judging the content contained within the body of this article, it should be relatively easy to assume where I stand on the issue, however I think it best to explicitly outline where I stand on the issue now that I have provided ample evidence in support. While an extreme view, even among my peers who spend most of their time within the digital realm, I believe that in the age of the internet copyright is a holdover of the past that is best to be forgotten about like the act of turning in papers written on scrolls or only passing knowledge orally. Personally, I am of the mind that the best works of humanity have yet to exist, will exist only through the continued use of technology, and will never exist if the current copyright system is allowed to continue unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following the discussions on this topic outlined above, it certainly seems necessary to rethink or totally abolish the use of copyright when it pertains to works that can and should so easily be shared within society today. The laws that were created and expanded upon before the internet was a commonality should not still be what governs the actions using its power. The world itself is a better place following the dissemination of knowledge and copyright laws only serve to go against the grain of time. Following this discussion, it looks like it might be time to update those laws America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-center&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Works Cited&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;About Piracy. (n.d.). Retrieved January 18, 2018, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.riaa.com/resources-learning/about-piracy/&quot;&gt;https://www.riaa.com/resources-learning/about-piracy/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Article 1, Section 8, Clause 8. (2000). Retrieved January 18, 2018, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://press-    pubs.uchicago.edu/founders/tocs/a1_8_8.html&quot;&gt;http://press-    pubs.uchicago.edu/founders/tocs/a1_8_8.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;BITTON, M. (2012). RETHINKING THE ANTI-COUNTERFEITING TRADE AGREEMENT’S CRIMINAL COPYRIGHT ENFORCEMENT MEASURES. The Journal of Criminal Law and Criminology (1973-), 102(1), 67-117. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jstor.org/stable/23145786&quot;&gt;http://www.jstor.org/stable/23145786&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;COPYRIGHT TERM EXTENSION. (n.d.). Retrieved January 17, 2018, from     &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.copyright.gov/legislation/s505.pdf&quot;&gt;https://www.copyright.gov/legislation/s505.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Geiger, C. (2017). Copyright as an access right: Securing cultural participation through the    protection of creators’ interests. In GIBLIN R. &amp;amp; WEATHERALL K. (Eds.), What if we could reimagine copyright? (pp. 73-110). Acton: ANU Press. Retrieved from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctt1q1crjg.6&quot;&gt;http://www.jstor.org/stable/j.ctt1q1crjg.6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kunzru, H. (2015, July 03). Dune, 50 years on: how a science fiction novel changed the     world. Retrieved January 18, 2018, from     &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2015/jul/03/dune-50-years-on-science-fiction-novel-world&quot;&gt;https://www.theguardian.com/books/2015/jul/03/dune-50-years-on-science-fiction-novel-world&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mick, J. (2013, January 21). Nearly Half of Americans Pirate Casually, But Pirates Purchase     More Legal Content. Retrieved January 18, 2018, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dailytech.com/NearlyHalfofAmericansPirateCasuallyButPiratesPurchaseMoreLegalContent/article29702.htm&quot;&gt;http://www.dailytech.com/NearlyHalfofAmericansPirateCasuallyButPiratesPurchaseMoreLegalContent/article29702.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mitchell, K. (2011, June 13). Where Do Morals Come From? Retrieved January 18, 2018, from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wiringthebrain.com/2011/06/where-do-morals-come-from.html&quot;&gt;http://www.wiringthebrain.com/2011/06/where-do-morals-come-from.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reynolds, G. (2014). Ethics in Information Technology. Cengage Learning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swartz , A. (2008, July). Guerilla Open Access Manifesto. Retrieved January 18, 2018, from     &lt;a href=&quot;https://archive.org/stream/GuerillaOpenAccessManifesto/Goamjuly2008_djvu.txt&quot;&gt;https://archive.org/stream/GuerillaOpenAccessManifesto/Goamjuly2008_djvu.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wu, T. (2003). When Code Isn’t Law. Virginia Law Review, 89(4), 679-751.doi:10.2307/3202374&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;17 U.S. Code § 107 - Limitations on exclusive rights: Fair use. (n.d.). Retrieved January 18,   2018, from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/17/107&quot;&gt;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/17/107&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;17 U.S. Code § 506 - Criminal offenses. (n.d.). Retrieved January 18, 2018, from     &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/17/506&quot;&gt;https://www.law.cornell.edu/uscode/text/17/506&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html">Warning: This post is very long. Read at your own risk. Also as part of my class discussed previously, I had to write a term paper on any topic that my little heart desired, as long as it related to the class. The topic was copyright law in the online realm, and what follows is the paper. Enjoy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rest Assured</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/22/rest-assured.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rest Assured" /><published>2018-01-22T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/22/rest-assured</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/22/rest-assured.html">&lt;p&gt;The website for Rest Assured Home Inspections LLC was redesigned to make it more
attractive for users, allowing it’s content to be more easily understood, and
flow better among various screen sizes. The previous website had the content,
however it was laid out in lack luster way, and was optimized for desktop while
being almost unusable on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Straying from my usual design patterns, which closely blend standard bootstrap
elements with the flatter aspects of the material design guidelines by Google, I
chose to keep the site almost entirely native bootstrap, using a darker theme to
align with the original site. The site consists of three main pages: a basic
landing page utilizing rows and columns to layout content, an about page that
contains a manifesto from the company owner, and a page that contains reviews of
the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The page was created using the Jekyll static site generating framework, is
hosted on a Centos 7 server being served by the Apache webserver, and is located
behind an Nginx load-balancer also running on a Centos 7 server. The TLS
ertificate for the site is provided by Let’s Encrypt, and is also being served
by the Nginx load-balancer. The repo for the site can be found my personal
Gitlab, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gitlab.doug-skinner.com/root/restassured&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The website for Rest Assured Home Inspections LLC was redesigned to make it more attractive for users, allowing it’s content to be more easily understood, and flow better among various screen sizes. The previous website had the content, however it was laid out in lack luster way, and was optimized for desktop while being almost unusable on mobile.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Mushroom Redesign</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/19/Mushroom-Redesign.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mushroom Redesign" /><published>2018-01-19T11:01:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-19T11:01:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/19/Mushroom-Redesign</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/19/Mushroom-Redesign.html">&lt;p&gt;While browsing reddit the other day I came upon a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/learnpython/comments/7q8qka/i_made_a_rough_draft_of_a_flask_app_that_accepts/&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; to a newer Github repo that someone was working on. That repo was &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brettvanderwerff/Mushroom-Map-Maker&quot;&gt;Mushroom Map Maker&lt;/a&gt; and now, mushrooms aren’t normally my thing, however I always like seeing what others are working on so I thought I would take a look. And functionality was great, the search worked perfectly, and even properly gave errors if the input was missing. The aesthetics of the page however left a little to be desired so I thought I would download it and take a look at what I could do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original landing page looked like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_starting_image.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it was obvious that the creater, &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/brettvanderwerff&quot;&gt;brettvanderwerff&lt;/a&gt;, was using bootstrap 3 based on the basic jumbotron and navbar. Now, bootstrap 3 is the older version and using bootstrap 4 would be easier, but it shouldn’t be too hard. Before I begin, I should point at that the changes to the actual repo were all done inline to not include another file in the repository, but will be represented below as if there were an actual custom css file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first change that I made was to indicate the actual page the user was using on the navbar, as to begin with it only ever had the active class on the “Home” link. This was as simple as adding a page variable to the flask routing that returned the name of the page, and did an if statement for each link to add the class if necessary. No other visual changes yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing that I did was to actually remove the standard active class, and implement my own version at first just changing the color of the link text. I also opted to make the background color of the navbar white instead of the default grey-ish. Our custom css file would look like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
.active-link {
  color: blue;
}

.navbar-bg {
  background-color: white;
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the landing page now looked like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_new_navbar.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, do deal with the actual content of the index page. The content was already within a container, which was good. First I pulled the instructions “Select “Search for a Mushroom” on the navigation bar to begin.” onto the main jumbotron. Then, to stop the page from seeming like it was shouting at you, I lowered the title “The Mushroom Map” to be an h2 instead of an h1. I also used the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;small&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag for the version number within that h2 to apply some built in boot-strappy styling. Separating the heading of that content from the body with an &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;hr /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; also gives some breathing room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, taking after the cards that became popular with Google’s Material Design guidelines, I opted to fashion the jumbotron holding the content as a card with a white background with a slight shadow. Our css file now contains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
.active-link {
  color: blue;
}

.navbar-bg {
  background-color: white;
}

.card {
  background-color: white;
  box-shadow: 1px 3px 5px 3px rgba(204, 204, 204, 0.3);
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the landing page now appears like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_card_index.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then to soften up the appearance of the links I opted to change the color to a softer shade of blue. Changing the color of the links to be less in your face may seem like a small change, but I’ve repeatedly found that by doings so it makes the page appear more friendly and welcoming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our custom file is now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
.active-link {
  color: blue;
}

.navbar-bg {
  background-color: white;
}

.card {
  background-color: white;
  box-shadow: 1px 3px 5px 3px rgba(204, 204, 204, 0.3);
}

a {
  color: #17a2b8;
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the landing page now appears like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_link_color.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now switching gears to the actual functionality of the site, the original search page looked like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_original_search.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the navbar changes that were made before that carried over, and by moving the content into a jumbotron just like before the content now mostly matches the homepage. It’s just a matter of cleaning it up. By making those changes, which doesn’t require a change to the css file, the page looks like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_card_search.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While that form is functional, it would appear better to use the form-groups that bootstrap provides to shape the label and the input. The code to do that is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
&amp;lt;div class=&quot;form-group&quot;&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;label for=&quot;example&quot;&amp;gt;Example&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;input class=&quot;form-control&quot; name=&quot;example&quot; type=&quot;text&quot;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now the page looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_form_groups.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, to take advantage of larger screens I moved the examples over to a second column. Once the screen got below the bootstrap’s defined medium screen size it then converts to being stacked like how it was. It now appears like so on larger screens:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_two_column.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original search page did alert the user if they had errors entering when submitting the form, however to make the look of the match the original, I modified them to both be alerts with the danger class. The danger class is a built in Bootstrap element that can be added to most text tags that makes the font color red, and in the case of the alerts also makes the background a lighter shade of red to really emphasize the text. A screenshot of the new change is below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_alerts.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, The example list was modified to be a dictionary list. Like changing the sizes of the card titles, this was done to make the page seem less in your face, while still providing the information. See below for the difference:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_d_list.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the last major change was to make the search look better by just adding some padding for mobile. While a minor change, the extra space makes the applications interface flow better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our custom file is now:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;
.active-link {
  color: blue;
}

.navbar-bg {
  background-color: white;
}

.card {
  background-color: white;
  box-shadow: 1px 3px 5px 3px rgba(204, 204, 204, 0.3);
}

a {
  color: #17a2b8;
}

mobile_padding {
  padding-bottom: 1em;
}

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that padding class is applied to the column containing the search form. The final product looks like below, shown in desktop and phone sized screens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_final_desk.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;rounded img-fluid shadow&quot; src=&quot;/img/post_images/mushroom_final_phone.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading the whole way through, I hoped it helped anyone that made it this far. As always, feel free to send me an email to the address below with any questions or comments.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Design" /><summary type="html">While browsing reddit the other day I came upon a link to a newer Github repo that someone was working on. That repo was Mushroom Map Maker and now, mushrooms aren’t normally my thing, however I always like seeing what others are working on so I thought I would take a look. And functionality was great, the search worked perfectly, and even properly gave errors if the input was missing. The aesthetics of the page however left a little to be desired so I thought I would download it and take a look at what I could do.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Replacing Characters Within Smarty Templating</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/18/Replacing-Characters-Smarty.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Replacing Characters Within Smarty Templating" /><published>2018-01-18T11:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-18T11:00:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/18/Replacing-Characters-Smarty</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/18/Replacing-Characters-Smarty.html">&lt;p&gt;Another quick one, while at work today needed to strip a few characters out of a
string, namely [ and ] as they were causing issues with some other string
manipulation further down the line. All I had to do was turn this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;{variable}&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Into this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;{variable|replace:&quot;[&quot;:&quot;&quot;|replace:&quot;]&quot;:&quot;&quot;}&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easy enough, right?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Development" /><summary type="html">Another quick one, while at work today needed to strip a few characters out of a string, namely [ and ] as they were causing issues with some other string manipulation further down the line. All I had to do was turn this:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Some Thoughts About Net Neutrality</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/17/Net-Neutrality-Thoughts.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some Thoughts About Net Neutrality" /><published>2018-01-17T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-17T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/17/Net-Neutrality-Thoughts</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/17/Net-Neutrality-Thoughts.html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I was asked to answer the below questions as part of the Information
Ethics class that I am taking, and I thought they would stand as a good
representation of my views on Net Neutrality. Enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you in favor of network neutrality going forward? Why or why not?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am entirely in favor of net neutrality. To believe anything else would be to go against the very essence of what makes the internet so great. The internet, since it was first invented by Tim Berners Lee, has long been a free for all where anyone can make the next big thing out of their garage. For most of the gian companies that we knwo today, i.e. Apple, Microsoft, Netflix, Facebook, and others, are only as big as they are because they were able to thrive as young companies on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the protection that these large companies used, that of every end point on the internet being treated equal, ever goes away it will almost certainly guarantee that competition among little companies will all but evaporate as the already established behemoths can simply pay to wipe them out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the threat of ISPs, private business firms, charging whatever they want to charge and that the market will bear?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By charging whatever they feel like charging to certain businesses the ISPs are trying to make their service what it isn’t. The goal of an INTERNET service provider is to provide service, i.e. access, to the internet. It is most certainly NOT to choose what goes over the internet. The role of the ISP is to act as a dumb pipe, the same way that a sewer does not care whether it carries water, excrement, or food shavings. Allowing an ISP to charge more for certain services would be the exact same as allowing sewage companies to charge more to carry water from your toilet than water from your sink.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What do the FCC and industry critics mean by “discriminatory behavior” towards selected Internet services? Does the FCC want to prevent ISPs from managing their networks?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discriminatory behavior on behalf of the ISPs would be to charge based on the type of traffic that goes over their network. Since a packet of video is no more damaging to a computer network than a packet of plain text, there is no reason that an ISP should be able to charge more for one than the other. The ISP is perfectly allowed to manage their networks, only so far as they are allowed to continue being a dumb pipe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does the FCC support metered pricing and/or Internet bandwidth caps?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, as long as the pricing reflects the usage and is non-discriminatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Major cities of the world have adopted “congestion pricing” in which cars pay a toll to enter the core of the city during daylight hours. Congestion pricing is also used to regulate demand by businesses for electricity. During the day when electricity is in high demand, many businesses pay a “demand” fee in addition to the regular charge for electricity. Why is the Internet any different?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the internet is different simply because the demand of the internet can be met much more simply than the demands of electricity. While the electricity of the United States has been regulated so everyone gets the same availability. The same is not true for ISPs. There are still multiple places within this country that have less than a 10mbps line as the fastest internet that they can get. Before the ISPs worry about charging their existings customers more and ruining thousands of internet based businesses, they should focus on actually providing the service they are supposed too to their customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If your business model depended for its success on millions of people being able to stream videos on demand (like YouTube) would you be in favor of net neutrality or against it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In favor of it. If my business model is dependant on as many people accessing it as possible, as most internet companies are, any extra charge per customer could be devestating.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html">Recently I was asked to answer the below questions as part of the Information Ethics class that I am taking, and I thought they would stand as a good representation of my views on Net Neutrality. Enjoy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/jekyll/update/2018/01/10/welcome-to-jekyll.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2018-01-10T23:14:41-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-10T23:14:41-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/jekyll/update/2018/01/10/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/jekyll/update/2018/01/10/welcome-to-jekyll.html">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">VPN, A Necessity?</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/05/VPN-Necessity.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="VPN, A Necessity?" /><published>2018-01-05T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-05T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/05/VPN-Necessity</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/05/VPN-Necessity.html">&lt;p&gt;Is using a VPN a necessecity for all internet users in this day and age? While
it may be a bit extreme, I do believe that any internet user that isn’t using a
VPN for their daily internet usage to protect their privacy and anonymity. There
are many reasons that an internet user should care about their privacy,
especially with the recent proposed change by the United States FCC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Internet Service Providers(ISPs) within the United States will soon be
able to charge users more depending on what softwares you actually use within
your billing period, none of that matters if you can’t be tracked. When using a
VPN, the only traffic that your ISP will be able to see and intercept will be to
the domain that hosts your VPN of choice. So while getting to Netflix may cost
you $0.02 a Mb, made up purely for this example but not out of the realms of
possibiity, if standard internet traffic only costs you $0.01 a Mb going through
the VPN which will appear as standard traffic lowers the costs that you will be
facing by half.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another big use of VPNs is to provide the same functionality of hiding your
traffic from others that may be looking to snoop it on the same network. This is
especially a problem on public WiFi that you may find in hotels, coffee shops,
and increasingly other public areas, as anyone that is on the same network as
you has the ability to see all traffic on this network. Another common issue
that standard internet users may encounter is fake public networks, such as a
mailicious individual that broadcasts an accesible network with the name “Free
Starbucks WiFi” from a computer that they own. Many internet users may connect
to the WiFi without a second thought, but through using a VPN to browse the
internet the malicious individual will not be able to easily see the traffic
that is being generated nor its intended destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While these aren’t the only reasons that someone should use a VPN, they are
among the most popular. I do encourage everyone that comes across this post to
seriously evaluate for themselves whether they need a VPN. As to what company to
use for your VPN, that is a matter that I will not step into, instead advising
each person to evaluate the various options on their own.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html">Is using a VPN a necessecity for all internet users in this day and age? While it may be a bit extreme, I do believe that any internet user that isn’t using a VPN for their daily internet usage to protect their privacy and anonymity. There are many reasons that an internet user should care about their privacy, especially with the recent proposed change by the United States FCC.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fixing Mysql Replication</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/02/Fixing-Mysql_Replication.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fixing Mysql Replication" /><published>2018-01-02T11:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-02T11:00:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/02/Fixing-Mysql_Replication</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/02/Fixing-Mysql_Replication.html">&lt;p&gt;Quick one. If you have a master and slave MySQL setup, if the slaves are
reporting replication failures BUT have a status that is simply waiting for the
next command, simply restarting MySQl should fix the issue. Sometimes a simple
restart is the answer.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Development" /><summary type="html">Quick one. If you have a master and slave MySQL setup, if the slaves are reporting replication failures BUT have a status that is simply waiting for the next command, simply restarting MySQl should fix the issue. Sometimes a simple restart is the answer.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New Year</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/01/New-Year.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New Year" /><published>2018-01-01T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-01T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/01/New-Year</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/01/01/New-Year.html">&lt;p&gt;Another year, another chance to make declarations about the goals that one hopes
to accomplish in the next 365 days. Writing down goals, especially in a semi
public place such as the internet, is one of the major steps to take in ensuring
that those goals actually succeed. Well, this is mine, in no particular order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Post here on this blog a major post at least once a week.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Release a new project or big update for a project every month.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Post a picture that I’m proud of every week.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of this month I should be able to see if all of these goals actually
come to fruition, and will make any adjustments as needed.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html">Another year, another chance to make declarations about the goals that one hopes to accomplish in the next 365 days. Writing down goals, especially in a semi public place such as the internet, is one of the major steps to take in ensuring that those goals actually succeed. Well, this is mine, in no particular order.</summary></entry></feed>