<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-05-18T17:23:24-04:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/</id><title type="html">Doug Skinner’s Blog</title><subtitle>My own thoughts and opinions on software engineering topics, wider technology, people, and what ever else comes up.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Starting Anew</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/05/18/Redesign.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting Anew" /><published>2018-05-18T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-18T12:00:00-04:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/05/18/Redesign</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/writing/2018/05/18/Redesign.html">&lt;p&gt;While going over what I need to do in life after leaving college, I realized that I wasn’t happy with the content of my website.
So I changed it. The new design is simplistic, and features the posts at the forefront. I’ll be utilizing it more now,
and some of the old posts might resurface. But it’ll be interesting to see how it goes.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Thoughts" /><summary type="html">While going over what I need to do in life after leaving college, I realized that I wasn’t happy with the content of my website. So I changed it. The new design is simplistic, and features the posts at the forefront. I’ll be utilizing it more now, and some of the old posts might resurface. But it’ll be interesting to see how it goes.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Converter</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/04/21/Converter.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Converter" /><published>2018-04-21T13:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-04-21T13:00:00-04:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/04/21/Converter</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/04/21/Converter.html">&lt;p&gt;Converter is a simple web wrapper around the youtube-dl command line tool that
allows one to download a youtube video into either an mp3 or mp4 file. While I’m
sure anyone browsing Github can easily run the youtube-dl script yourself, this
is built for you to offer a solution for friends or family members. There are
many sites that offer the same functionality, but they are normally covered in
ads and links to not so great sites, so you can host this one on your personal
network to allow them to go to a trusted resource.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://converter.doug-skinner.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written as a simple Flask application, it can either be run locally after
installing the required packages, or it is tested to run on a Centos 7 server.
An install script is included to make setup easier on a server. Hosting your own
copy of the software on a Centos 7 server is easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Setup the Centos 7 server&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run the following commands as root
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;yum install git -y&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;git clone https://github.com/doug-skinner/converter.git&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;cd converter&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;./install.sh&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;After that script runs, you should be all set by navigating to the ip address of
the server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html">Converter is a simple web wrapper around the youtube-dl command line tool that allows one to download a youtube video into either an mp3 or mp4 file. While I’m sure anyone browsing Github can easily run the youtube-dl script yourself, this is built for you to offer a solution for friends or family members. There are many sites that offer the same functionality, but they are normally covered in ads and links to not so great sites, so you can host this one on your personal network to allow them to go to a trusted resource.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prex</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/02/09/Prex.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prex" /><published>2018-02-09T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-09T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/02/09/Prex</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/02/09/Prex.html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;P&lt;/strong&gt;ython &lt;strong&gt;R&lt;/strong&gt;eguler &lt;strong&gt;Ex&lt;/strong&gt;pression handler is a basic script written in
Python (shocking I know) that reads in a regex string and the file to search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rather than using the built in regex class/parser, Prex then creates a
&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Deterministic_finite_automaton&quot;&gt;DFA&lt;/a&gt; from the
input regex string, to allow the regex to be processed. After reading in the
input file, separated line by line on newline characters (‘\n’), the script then
feeds in each line to the internal DFA character by character. If the DFA
reaches the end state, it then returns the starting index, ending index, and all
characters that match the regex printing that info to stdout.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html">The Python Reguler Expression handler is a basic script written in Python (shocking I know) that reads in a regex string and the file to search.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Flask Template</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/23/flask-template.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Flask Template" /><published>2018-01-23T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-23T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/23/flask-template</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/23/flask-template.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is still a work in progress&lt;/strong&gt;. This project aims to be a template for other web developers to base their
projects off of. The template includes a couple of classes that handle creating
users, logging in users, and eventually managing users. Each user upon logging
in is presented with their own control panel for whatever service they are
logging into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As stated above, this project is a work in progress, and I will be posting updates below as they happen, and updating through blog posts.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html">This is still a work in progress. This project aims to be a template for other web developers to base their projects off of. The template includes a couple of classes that handle creating users, logging in users, and eventually managing users. Each user upon logging in is presented with their own control panel for whatever service they are logging into.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rest Assured</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/22/rest-assured.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rest Assured" /><published>2018-01-22T12:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-01-22T12:00:00-05:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/22/rest-assured</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2018/01/22/rest-assured.html">&lt;p&gt;The website for Rest Assured Home Inspections LLC was redesigned to make it more
attractive for users, allowing it’s content to be more easily understood, and
flow better among various screen sizes. The previous website had the content,
however it was laid out in lack luster way, and was optimized for desktop while
being almost unusable on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Straying from my usual design patterns, which closely blend standard bootstrap
elements with the flatter aspects of the material design guidelines by Google, I
chose to keep the site almost entirely native bootstrap, using a darker theme to
align with the original site. The site consists of three main pages: a basic
landing page utilizing rows and columns to layout content, an about page that
contains a manifesto from the company owner, and a page that contains reviews of
the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The page was created using the Jekyll static site generating framework, is
hosted on a Centos 7 server being served by the Apache webserver, and is located
behind an Nginx load-balancer also running on a Centos 7 server. The TLS
ertificate for the site is provided by Let’s Encrypt, and is also being served
by the Nginx load-balancer. The repo for the site can be found my personal
Gitlab, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gitlab.doug-skinner.com/root/restassured&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html">The website for Rest Assured Home Inspections LLC was redesigned to make it more attractive for users, allowing it’s content to be more easily understood, and flow better among various screen sizes. The previous website had the content, however it was laid out in lack luster way, and was optimized for desktop while being almost unusable on mobile.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Capital Clean Ups</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2016/06/01/capital-clean-ups.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Capital Clean Ups" /><published>2016-06-01T14:39:36-04:00</published><updated>2016-06-01T14:39:36-04:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2016/06/01/capital-clean-ups</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2016/06/01/capital-clean-ups.html">&lt;p&gt;The Capital Clean Ups website was created for a small business in my local area that focuses on removing junk from commercial and residential locations. It was primarily used to advertise that the company existed, and also to showcase the services offered. Overall, it was a very basic website and done more as a favor than as a learning experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;This project was my second major entry into web development, and consisted of a Python Flask backend with a front-end mostly in JQuery. The database layer is MySQL. It was hosted on a web server that I ran, running Centos 7.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just kidding. This project has since been updated to use bootstrap 4 and is
generated using Jekyll. No more database or flask for a 5 page static site.
Still hosted by me on a Centos 7 server.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html">The Capital Clean Ups website was created for a small business in my local area that focuses on removing junk from commercial and residential locations. It was primarily used to advertise that the company existed, and also to showcase the services offered. Overall, it was a very basic website and done more as a favor than as a learning experience.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Risk Raiders</title><link href="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2016/05/01/risk-raiders.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Risk Raiders" /><published>2016-05-01T14:39:36-04:00</published><updated>2016-05-01T14:39:36-04:00</updated><id>htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2016/05/01/risk-raiders</id><content type="html" xml:base="htpps://www.doug-skinner.com/projects/2016/05/01/risk-raiders.html">&lt;p&gt;The Risk Raiders website was developed during an internship with Ernst &amp;amp; Young my sophomore year, in order to allow financial firms to more easily control their Third Party Risk Management. Third Party Risk Management is one of the most crucial aspects of the relationship between a financial institution and the various third party vendors that they work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because allowing a third party access to a financial institutions business critical information, servers, and software requires the financial institution to trust the third party entirely. This trust stems from the financial institution following a standardized cycle for forming a new third party relationship. This cycle follows the creation and eventual ending of the relationship between the two parties, and consists of five phases. The phases, in the order that they occur are planning, due diligence, contract negotiation, monitoring, and finally termination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When forming a new third party relationship, the third party invariably introduces risk to the financial institution. This risk can be anything that could negatively impact the financial institutions profit, current reputation, relationships with other institutions, or business longevity. The risk that is there at the start of the relationship is what’s known as inherent risk. This risk can be very high or very low depending on how well the third party has mitigated this risk. Even though the third party may have lowered the risk, it is still the responsibility of the financial institution to try to lower this risk even further. The financial institution does this by placing controls on the relationship between the two parties. Once these controls are in place most of the inherent risk should be removed. The risk that is left over after the controls are put into place is considered the residual risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The functionality of the website was such that a member of the financial firm could log into a web interface and view a matrix of scores of the various third parties that they are partnered with. This allows the financial firm to quickly assess all of their relationships and make decisions based upon them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project was my first major entry into web development, and consisted of a Python Flask backend with a front-end utilizing in JQuery. The database layer is MySQL. It was hosted on a web server that I ran, running Centos 7.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html">The Risk Raiders website was developed during an internship with Ernst &amp;amp; Young my sophomore year, in order to allow financial firms to more easily control their Third Party Risk Management. Third Party Risk Management is one of the most crucial aspects of the relationship between a financial institution and the various third party vendors that they work with.</summary></entry></feed>